<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd" >
  

<a name="Related persons as performer of the prescription"> </a>
<h3>Related persons as performer of the prescription</h3>
<p>The requested performer in a referral prescription is typically a reference to a practitioner but it could also be reference to related person.  Typically the performer shall be referred by a business identifier or Reference.display.</p>
<p>It is RECOMMENDED in case of a related person as performer, the related person is included using the <a href="https://www.hl7.org/fhir/references.html#contained">contained mechanism</a>.</p>
 <a name="The procedure or observation executing the referral prescription"> </a>
 <h3>The procedure or observation executing the referral prescription</h3>
 <p>A procedure or observation resource typically execute the referral prescription. As such, they shall be made available on the system where the ServiceRequest resides and refer to the ServiceRequest resource using their basedOn field.</p> 
<a name="Specifics concerning the referral prescription for nursing"> </a>
 <h3>Specifics concerning the referral prescription for nursing</h3>
 <a name="Availability of prescriber"> </a>
   <h4>Availability of prescriber</h4>
 <p>If needed, the availability of a prescriber SHALL be given using a PractitionerRole resource referring to the Practitioner that is the prescriber of the ServiceRequest.</p> 
  <a name="Signature and date of signature"> </a>
  <h4>Signature and date of signature</h4>
 <p>If needed, a signature SHALL be given using a Provenance resource referring to the ServiceRequest.</p> 
  <a name="Specifics concerning the referral prescription for diagnostic imaging"> </a>
  <h3>Specifics concerning the referral prescription for diagnostic imaging</h3>
  <a name="Contactinformation of the requester"> </a>
      <h4>Contactinformation of the requester</h4>
 <p>The creator of the diagnostic imaging referral prescription SHALL take extra note to
 provide contact information of the requesting party. Typically,
 a phone number is expected to be available.</p> 

<a name="Referring to previous imaging studies"> </a>
      <h4>Referring to previous imaging studies</h4>
 <p>The imaging request is not intended to give an exhaustive overview of previous imaging studies concerning the patient.
 However, when a reference to a previous imaging is relevant to the current one, this SHALL be referenced.</p> 

<a name="Guidance around supporting information"> </a>
      <h4>Guidance around supporting information</h4>
	  <p>The profile contains a few elements that can contain supporting information. It SHALL be clear, these
	  elements are there to only include information that is considered relevant within the context of
	  this prescription. These elements are not to be used to construct an exhaustive dossier of the patient.</p>
	 
  <a name="Specifics concerning the referral prescription for physiotherapy"> </a>
  <h3>Specifics concerning the referral prescription for physiotherapy</h3>
 <p>N/A</p> 
 <a name="Specifics concerning the referral prescription for laboratory"> </a>
   <h3>Specifics concerning the referral prescription for laboratory</h3>
<a name="Priority of the order"> </a>
      <h4>Priority of the order</h4>
      <p>The priority is expressed in the .priority element giving 4 priority codes. 
      It SHALL be noted these different codes have a <a href="https://hl7.org/fhir/R4/valueset-request-priority.html">clear definition</a> in the FHIR specification.
     </p>
	 
	 <a name="Use of communication channels"> </a>
      <h4>Use of communication channels</h4>
	  <p>Is is sometimes asked to communicate results via ad hoc communication channels. Parties SHALL always adhere to any national or European privacy law in place. </p>
	 
	 

   <a name="Sending more than one testing code in the prescription"> </a>
      <h4>Sending more than one testing code in the prescription</h4>
      <p>Both fields .code and orderDetail are allowed to contain testing codes. The base FHIR resource allows for only
      one code in the .code element and multiple codes using the .orderDetail element</p>
      <p>The best way to use these two elements is left to the discretion of the implementer. When reading
      an order, implementers SHALL always
      take note of these two elements when determining the testing codes that are in the order. </p>
      <p>When more than one code is present in the prescription, they SHALL be different codes.</p>
   
   <a name="Connecting specimen and tests in the order"> </a>
   <h4>Connecting specimen and tests in the order</h4>
   <p>Although the order allows for multiple testing codes (using orderDetail) and 
   references to multiple specimen the implementer SHALL be aware
   of the following to ensure there is no ambiguity in the order. The order SHALL fall in one of the following categories:</p>
  <ul>
  <li>No references to specimen are given but the testing codes given are clear on the specimen.</li>
  <li>One or more references to a specimen are given and from the testing code(s) given it is clear what test uses what specimen.</li>
  <li>A connection between a testing code and a specimen cannot be deduced from the testing code: for every specimen
   there is one order created only containing the testing code(s) for that specimen. 
   If still needed to combine multiple orders 
   that are created in such a way: the .requisition element SHALL be used where a common Identifier is given.</li>

  </ul>
   
   <a name="Physical workflow for the specimen"> </a>
   <h4>Workflow for the specimen</h4>
   <p>It is noted here, the physical workflow concerning the specimen is considered out of scope in this implementation guide.
   To enable any future initiative to deal with specimen, this guide does provide a national identifier naming system but it is fully
   expected there will be instances of the laboratory prescription
   where no specimen identifier is known at the time of making the prescription.</p>
   <a name="Intent/status of prescription"> </a>
   <h4>Intent/status of prescription</h4>
   <p>A laboratory prescription might use different specific elements depending on the workflow. It SHALL be noted this is of
course limited to what is possible concerning when the specimen was accepted</p>
<ul>
   <li>The .status normally remains 'active' until the request is fulfilled. If needed the status can be changed to 'revoked' or 'entered-in-error' to cancel the request.</li>
<li>The original order of a laboratory prescription SHALL be made by having .intent as 'original-order'</li>
<li>Appending the request with extra orders can be done by using the intent 'order' and referencing the original order using the .basedOn element </li>
<li>Replacing the order can be done by using the intent 'order' and referencing the original order using the .replaces element</li>
<li>If needed, the .intent can be 'reflex-order' or 'filler-order' with a reference to the original order using the .basedOn element</li>
</ul>  
</div>